# TOUSEEF SHAHBAZ

+92 323 8459887

Web Developer

tosif.shahbax@gmail.com



178-U Block, DHA, Lahore 🚹



## SUMMARY

A skilled WEB Developer with over 3 years of experience, currently at CureMd, enhancing healthcare applications using Angular/asp/React.js/WordPress. Previously developed responsive web apps at BRAINSLOGIC with React.js/Next.js and integrated front and back-end systems. As an intern at NETSOL, contributed to web application development with Bootstrap. Certified in React, JavaScript, and HTML/CSS from Meta.

# **EDUCATION**

# University of Management and Technology

Bachelor's Degree in Software Engineering 2019 – 2023

## **Garrison College**

Intermediate in Computer Science 2017 – 2019

## **SKILLS**

- React.js /Next.js
- Angular / WordPress
- Bootstrap / MUI
- CSS
- Python /JS
- GitHub
- Debugging
- Communication
- Presentation

# **PROJECTS**

- FRENZY (Shopping website)
- AOUTOBIDUP (FYP: next.js, Django)
- LAWMINDER (React.js, mongo dB)
- Royal Fleet (royal-fleet.vercel.app)
- TRAVEL AGENCY (C#)
- Oncentric (health care website)

# CERTIFICATIONS

- REACT FROM META
  - (HTTPS://WWW.COURSERA.ORG/ACCOUNT/ACCO MPLISHMENTS/VERIFY/LYBR CHGYEULC)
- JAVASCRIPT FROM META
  - (HTTPS://WWW.COURSERA.ORG/ACCOUNT/ACCO MPLISHMENTS/VERIFY/AX5 NBE4NAGRK)
- HTML/CSS FROM META
  - (HTTPS://WWW.COURSERA.ORG/ACCOUNT/ACCO MPLISHMENTS/VERIFY/LUKU 7MUVMPAC)

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **Associate Front-End developer**

CureMD | January 2024 - Present

- Collaborating with cross-functional teams to contribute to the development and enhancement of a healthcare application using React.js and other relevant technologies.
- Implementing and optimizing user interfaces for a seamless and intuitive user experience. Conducting code reviews and ensuring the integration of front-end components with the backend.

### Web Developer

BrainsLogic | April 2022 - January 2024

- Collaborated with the design team to develop and maintain a responsive web application using React.js/Next.js and Bootstrap, Material-UI.
- Implemented new features and functionalities to enhance the user experience. Conducted regular code reviews and testing to ensure high-quality code. Handled confidential documents and maintained their proper organization
- Coordinated with backend developers to ensure seamless integration of frontend and backend components

#### **Development Intern**

NETSOL | September 2021- February 2022

- Assisted with the development of a web application using Bootstrap. Worked with the design team to ensure a visually appealing and responsive user interface.
- Conducted testing and debugging to ensure a smooth user experience.

### LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/touseef-shahbaz-f212200/

#### Github

https://github.com/Touseef1122